[
{"type":"header","version":"4.9.2","comment":"Export to JSON plugin for PHPMyAdmin"},
{"type":"database","name":"school"},
{"type":"table","name":"riph","database":"school","data":
[
{"no":"1","question":"Founder of International Association of historians of Asia?","answer":"Gregorio F. Zaide","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"2","question":"The symbol of the American Flag?","answer":"Emblem of Freedom and Symbol of altruism","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"3","question":"General Leonard Wood was known to be cognizant in the Liberation of____?","answer":"Cuba","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"4","question":"____ The President of the USA who advised Congress of the America <br> to fulfill their promise of independence since the loyalty form <br>the Philippines was achieved.","answer":"Calvin ","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"5","question":"A multi-awarded author who wrote 67 books and more than 500 article <br> about history?","answer":"Gregorio F. Zaide","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"6","question":"Gregorio F. Zaide also known as?","answer":"Histographer","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"7","question":"Gregorio F. Zaide had served as the mayor of his hometown _____ from 1971-1997","answer":"Pausatan","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"8","question":"Little island south of leyte?","answer":"Limasawa","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"9","question":"Beach at the mountain of the Agusan River?","answer":"Masao","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"10","question":"A book written by F. Colin published in Madrid in 1663?","answer":"Labor of Evangelista","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"11","question":"It means love of ones country?","answer":"Nationalism","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"12","question":"An attemt of the indios to overthrow the Spanish government?","answer":"Cavite Mutiny","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"13","question":"A book written by Fr, Combes printed in Madrid in 1667?","answer":"Historia De Mindanao Y Jolo","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"14","question":"True or False:<br> Gov. Gen. Rafael Izquierdo is the spanish governor general who magnified the <br>1872 event.","answer":"True","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"15","question":"True or False:<br> Secularization attempt to Filipinize the parishes in the Philippines.","answer":"True","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"16","question":"True or False:<br> Mark Sebastian Elcano, He commanded the Victor ship.","answer":"False","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"17","question":"True or False:<br> Wenceslao Retana, he annotated the book written by Fr, Combes after 230 years.","answer":"True","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"18","question":"True or False:<br> Joseph Moteroy Vidal, Spanish historian who documented the 1872 event.","answer":"False","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"19","question":"True or False:<br> Maguindanao, it Means the place and the dwellers of river.","answer":"False","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"20","question":"True or False:<br> Father Pio Pi, Priest who wrote the shorter version of retraction of Rizal.","answer":"True","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"21","question":"True or False:<br> Polo Y Servicio, A forced labor requiring the natives to render Services to Spanish government.","answer":"True","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"22","question":"True or False:<br>January 20, 1872, was the feast day of the virgin of Loreto?","answer":"True","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"23","question":"True or False:<br>:Quezon City ,Where is Pugan Lawin located.","answer":"True","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"24","question":"Filipino Soldier who lead the cavite Mutiny?","answer":"Sergeant La Madrid","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"25","question":"Form death sentence given to the masterminds of the Mutiny?","answer":"Garrote","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"26","question":"Author of the educational decree which promoted the fusion of secretarian <br> schools run by the friars?","answer":"Segismundo Moret","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"27","question":"French writer who witnessesd the execution of the three priest?","answer":"Edmund Plauchut","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"28","question":"The school which will improve the standard of education in the philippines?","answer":"Philippine Institute","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"29","question":"Tragic Event which served as the moving forces that shaped the Filipino nationalism","answer":"execution of Gomburza","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"30","question":"Date of the execution of three priest","answer":"February 17, 1872","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"31","question":"Filipino scholar and research,who wrote the Filipino version of the cavite Mutiny?","answer":"Dr.Trinidad Hermenigildo pardo De Tavera","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"32","question":"When did the Pugad lawin happen?","answer":"August 23, 1896","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"33","question":"This event reflected the decision of the katipunan to stage a revolution againts spain?","answer":"Cry of Montalban","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"34","question":"Preist who claimed that he solemnized the wedding of Rizal and josephine Bracken","answer":"Fr. Vicente Balaguer","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"35","question":"He is the author of the 2 face of 1872 cavite Mutiny","answer":"Chris Antonette Piedad Pugay","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"36","question":"He author the title Cry of Balintawak","answer":"Guillermo Masangkay","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"37","question":"He found the document retraction of Jose Rizal","answer":"Fr. Manuel A. Gracia","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"38","question":"The author of the Cry of bahay toro","answer":"Santiago Alvarez","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"39","question":"He founded the filipino church","answer":"Gregorio aglipay","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"40","question":"Declaration Jurada English","answer":"affidavit","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"41","question":"Masoneria","answer":"Teachings of Masonry","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"42","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>The salas<br>Samar<br>Good Omens<br>Small uninhabited Island<br>Archipelago of San Lazaro<br><br><h3>Humunu</h3>","answer":"Small Uninhabited Island","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"43","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>The salas<br>Samar<br>Good Omens<br>Small uninhabited Island<br>Archipelago of San Lazaro<br><br><h3>Las Velas</h3>","answer":"The salas","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"44","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>The salas<br>Samar<br>Good Omens<br>Small uninhabited Island<br>Archipelago of San Lazaro<br><br><h3>Las Velas Latinas</h3>","answer":"Archipelago of san Lazaro","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"45","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>The salas<br>Samar<br>Good Omens<br>Small uninhabited Island<br>Archipelago of San Lazaro<br><br><h3>Ibabao</h3>","answer":"Samar","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"46","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>The salas<br>Samar<br>Good Omens<br>Small uninhabited Island<br>Archipelago of San Lazaro<br><br><h3>Buenas Senas</h3>","answer":"Good Omens","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"47","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>Fr. Dela Conception <br>Giovanni Carren<br>Fr. Combes<br>Fr. Colin<br>Fr. Joaquin de Zuniga<br><br><h3>Historia de Maguindanao</h3>","answer":"Fr. Colin","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"48","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>Fr. Dela Conception <br>Giovanni Carren<br>Fr. Combes<br>Fr. Colin<br>Fr. Joaquin de Zuniga<br><br><h3>Labor Evangelista</h3>","answer":"Giovanni Carren","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"49","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>Fr. Dela Conception <br>Giovanni Carren<br>Fr. Combes<br>Fr. Colin<br>Fr. Joaquin de Zuniga<br><br><h3>Giro Del Mundo</h3>","answer":"Fr. Colin","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"50","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>Fr. Dela Conception <br>Giovanni Carren<br>Fr. Combes<br>Fr. Colin<br>Fr. Joaquin de Zuniga<br><br><h3>History of the philippines</h3>","answer":"Fr. Dela Conception","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"51","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>Fr. Dela Conception <br>Giovanni Carren<br>Fr. Combes<br>Fr. Colin<br>Fr. Joaquin de Zuniga<br><br><h3>Historia de Pilipinas</h3>","answer":"Fr. Joaquin de Zuniga","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"52","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>Jose Montero y Vidal<br>Martinez de Zuniga<br>Antonio Pigaffeta<br>Transylvanus<br>Pablo Pastel<br><br><h3>Primo Viaggio Intormo al Mundo</h3>","answer":"Antonio Pigaffeta","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"53","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>Jose Montero y Vidal<br>Martinez de Zuniga<br>Antonio Pigaffeta<br>Transylvanus<br>Pablo Pastel<br><br><h3>De Muluccis Insult</h3>","answer":"Transylvanus","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"54","question":"Choose the correct Answer to Match the given word:<br>Jose Montero y Vidal<br>Martinez de Zuniga<br>Antonio Pigaffeta<br>Transylvanus<br>Pablo Pastel<br><br><h3>El Archipelago Filipino</h3>","answer":"Jose Montero y Vidal","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"55","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>On august 23,1896 there were almost 1,0000 of katipuneros met and carried out considerable debate and discussion about revolution","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"56","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Dr. Trinidad Herminigildo Pardo de Tavera documented the 2 face of cavite munity","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"57","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Chris Antonette T Piedad-Pugat wrote the Filipino version of the bloody incident in cavite","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"58","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Gregoria de Jesus is the founder and president of the Women's Chapter of the katipunan of the Philippines","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"59","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Sargeant La Madrid and the 250 men contingent launched an attack targeting the spanish officers","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"60","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The Philippines island has 65 volumes collection of documents","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"61","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Jose Vidal introduced rigid and strict policies that made the Filipinos move away from the spanish government out of disgust","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"62","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The version of the first cry occurred near Bulacan","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"63","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The butuan tradition was already in possession by the middle of the 18th century","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"64","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Maguindanao means massacre","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"65","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>One of the participants of the Philippine revolution of 1898 was Gregoria de Jesus","answer":"A","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"66","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The version of the first Cry occured on August 25, 1986","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"67","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>On January 20, 1871 about 300 men compromised of soldiers, laborers of the arsenal assasinated the commanding officer and Spanish officers in sight","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"68","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Members of native clergy was excuted by garote","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"69","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The central government of Americans welcomed an education decree","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"70","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>I believe that limasawa is the location of the first mass in the philippines","answer":"A","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"71","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Segismundo Moret Promoted the tusion of soctanon schools run by the friars into a school called Philippine Institute","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"72","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The defensa adios was written in pencil, while the retraction was in ink","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"73","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Professor Henry Otley Beyer published of an opuscule","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"74","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Cavite is where they mistock the fireworks as the sign for the attack","answer":"A","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"75","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Guillermo Masangkay is Bonifactio's Cousin","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"76","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Filipino Responded saying Revolt!!! after Aguinaldo held his speech","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"77","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Father of Gregorio de Jesus approved the marriage to Andres Bonifacio","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"78","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>People followed bonifacio to destroy their cedulas","answer":"A","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"79","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The Butuan claim rests for thirteen centuries","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"80","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Both colin and Combes exercises a strong influence over a subsequent writers","answer":"A","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"81","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Juan Sebastian de Elcano was a Spanish explorer of Bogue origin who completed the first circumsnavigation of the globe","answer":"A","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"82","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Fray Joaquin Martinez de Zuniga was one of the important writers who accepted the Butuan","answer":"A","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"83","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Gregoria de Jesus first husband is Julio Nakpil","answer":"A","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"84","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Father Sanchez is Risal'z Favorite Professor","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"85","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The execution of Dr. Jose Rizal takes place in Dapitan","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"86","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>There is only one account of the First Catholic Mass in the philippines","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"87","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The significance of the martyrdom of the GOMBURZA is questioned by historians","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"88","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Jose Rizal's essays go against the Catholic Faith","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"89","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Aguinaldo returned to the Philippines on May 19, 1889","answer":"A","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"90","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The assasination of Ninoy Aquino is an important historical event that fueled peoples anger and condemnation of the dictator","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"91","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>Corazon Aquino did not want to forge alliance with the United States because the latter was a known imporant ally of marcos","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"92","question":"Enter A if True, B if False<br>The conservative attitude of the youth toward sexuality did not change since the spanish period until the 1930s","answer":"B","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"93","question":"He wrote and published - Rizal Philippine Nationalist and Martyr","answer":"A. Coates","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"94","question":"The author of Biografia de Rizal","answer":"R. Palma","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"95","question":"Jesuits Superior in the Philippines during the time when Rizal was executed","answer":"Fr. P Pi","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"96","question":"He was the one who solemnized the marrage of Josephine Bracken","answer":"Fr. V. Balaguer","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"97","question":"He issued an affidavit recounting his involvement in the alleged retraction of Rizal","answer":"Fr. P Pi","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"98","question":"He managed to persuade Rizal to denounce Masonry and reeturn to Catholic fold","answer":"Fr. V. Balaguer","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"99","question":"When did Rizal made his retraction? Exact date & time without year(ex:Dec 1, 1:30pm)","answer":"December 29, 11:30pm","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"100","question":"In what month and year did the De Moluccis Insults first Printed","answer":"January 1523","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"101","question":"How many days did the Magellan's Expedition stayed at Mazaua","answer":"7 days","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"102","question":"He was the son of Melchora Aquino","answer":"Juan Ramos","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"103","question":"When did the katipunan discovered by the spaniards?","answer":"August 19,1896","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"104","question":"What age did Dr. Pio Valenzuela Joined the katipunan","answer":"23","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"105","question":"What year did the Cry of Pugad Lawin occured?","answer":"1896","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"106","question":"What did the katipunero tore during revolt","answer":"Cedula","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"107","question":"When did the Spanish friars uncover evidences of the katipunan plan","answer":"August 1896","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"108","question":"When did the Japanese attack Philippines 10 hours after Bombing the Pearl Harbor in Hawaii","answer":"December 8","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"109","question":"Which of the following was the immediate cause of the outbreak of the war of Philippine Independence<br>A. San Nicolas Incedent <br>B. Pasig River Incedent<br>C. San Juan Bridge Incedent","answer":"C","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"110","question":"Choose the answer that DOES NOT belong to the universities established during the American Era<br>A. CEU<br>B. Siliman University<br> C. FEU <br> D. PWU","answer":"C","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"111","question":"In what year Corazon Aquino is qouted in a CNN internal article as saying I'd like to be known as a woman of faith, somebody who believed in God and who believed in __________.<br>A. her Family<br>B. Politcsc herself<br>D. Her People","answer":"D","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"112","question":"He wrote and Published Rizal and published - RIZAL Philippine Nationalist and Martyr","answer":"Fr. P Pi","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"113","question":"The author of Biogragia de Rizal","answer":"Fr. V Balaguer","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"114","question":"First Stage in the development of the Civil government ","answer":"Phil Assembly","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"115","question":"give the 3 islands of the camotes Group (In order and separated with , comma)","answer":"Poro, Ponsor,Pacitan ne Poshan","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"116","question":"give the two americans responsible for the shift in opinion (In order and separated with , comma)","answer":"Emma Helen Blair,James Alexander Robertson","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"117","question":"Give the 2 Privileges that were abolished which caused the cavity munity (In order and separated with , comma","answer":"Non Payment of Tributes,Exemption from forced Labor","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"118","question":"Give the 3 Filipino Patriots Suspended from the practice of Law (In order and separated with , comma)","answer":"Joaquin Pardo de tavero,Antonio Ma Regidor, Jose Basa & Pid Basa","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"119","question":"Give the 3 person who pruposed the revolution","answer":"Teodoro Plata,Pio Valenzuela,Bricio Pantas","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"120","question":"Give the 2 Chieftains who attended the Mass","answer":"Rajah of Butuan, Raja of Mazaua","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"121","question":"Give at least 8 persons who attended the big meeting in Balintawak (in order and separated with , comma)","answer":"Bonifacio & Teodoro Plata,Emilio Jacinto & Pio Valenzuela,Aguedo Del Rosario,Tomas Remigio,Bricio Pontas","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"122","question":"Give 2 Pastells Published Works","answer":"Historia de mandana y jolo,Labor Evangelista","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"},
{"no":"123","question":"Bonus Question: Sino ang kamuka ni Andrei Castro na artista sa ABSCBN","answer":"James Reid","exam":"midterm","lesson":"1"}
]
}
]
